Morwarid Najafizada

Ontario, Canada | Phone: +1 (613) 698 – 7059 | LinkedIn: https://linkedIn: linkedIn: linkedIn: linkedIn.com/in/morwarid | Portfolio: morwarid1.github.io/ | GitHub: github.com/morwarid1 | Email:morwarid.najafizada@gmail.com | Tableau:public.tableau.com/profile/morwarid.najafizada#!/

SUMMARY

Data Analyst with three years of experience working with data. Strong problem-solving, analyzing, and researching skills. Experienced in modeling, interpreting, and reporting data. Recognized for maximizing performance by implementing and managing appropriate project analysis. Highly educated, possessing a Bachelor's Degree in Business Analytics and a Professional Certificate in Data Analytics and Data Immersion.

SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL, R,

Tools & Techniques: Tableau, Excel, Data Analysis, Quality assurance, Data Manipulation, Data Pipeline, Data Quality, Data Visualization, Data Mining, ETL, Databases, Relational Databases, Data Warehouse, Business Intelligence, Pandas, Numpy, Scikit Learn, Big Data Analytics, A/B testing, Power BI. Presentation Skills.

Algorithms: Supervised Learning, Unsupervised Learning, Regression, Classification, Clustering, K-Means, Decision Trees, Logistic Regression, Linear Regression

EXPERIENCE

Data Entry Clerk, UN Association in Canada

Dec 2019 - Present

- Expanded the portfolio of sponsors by tracking and processing monthly changes and troubleshooting in the database.
- Generated regular reports and data exports, including tax receipts, gift acknowledgments, and membership lists.
- Processed contact and gift donation into Raiser's Edge a fundraising and constituent relationship management (CRM) system and saved the department 30 hours of manual work each week.
- Grew 20+ sponsors and donors by assisting with research, including the capture of information in the appropriate database.

Research Assistant, University of Ottawa

Sep 2018 – Dec 2019

- Spearheaded the research team in data collection functions using qualitative and quantitative strategies.
- Oversaw the research team on data cleansing, managing, and visualizing.
- Analyzed and investigated relevant research datasets from 15+ public data sources.
- Assisted Professor and the research team of 10+ in projects applying data mining techniques and data integrity methods to our datasets.
- Conducted research projects using qualitative research methods such as content analysis of primary and secondary resources.
- Collaborated with the rest of the research team to write and build customized interactive reports and dashboards.

PROJECTS

COVID-19 in the US Descriptive Analysis, CareerFoundry (BootCamp)

Feb 2021

- Conducted an ad-hoc descriptive analysis of US COVID-19 metadata to find which states need urgent vaccinations and medical services.
- Build a Linear Regression model to predict the number of deaths in the upcoming season.
- Segmented the COVID-19 cases into different clusters to define vaccination strategy based on their age group and states.
- Identified the top 10 states for the urgent need of vaccinations and presented the result in dashboards and Excel reports.
- Technical Scope: scikit-learn, Stats Models API, Seaborn, MLR, Clustering, and Time-series Analysis.

Instacart Grocery Basket Exploratory Analysis, CareerFoundry

Dec 2020

- Performed exploratory analysis in Store's historical data of customers to derive insights and suggest strategies to better segmentation using Jupyter Notebooks and the Anaconda libraries manager.
- Analyzed different types of customers and created exclusion flags based on their loyalty, Region, age and family status, and demographic classification.
- Wrangled, aggregated, and merged the large datasets to achieve better insights and avoid potential risks.
- Identified days of the week, types of customers, top 5 products, and regions that need better marketing strategies.
- Generated the result in reports and dashboards to communicate insights to stakeholders.
- Technical Scope: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, OS, seaborn, and SciPy.

Rockbuster Stealth Database Project, CareerFoundry

Sep 2020

• launched a strategy for the new online video rental service using advanced SQL techniques such as common table expression, joining tables, data extraction, and build ETL Pipeline.

- Loaded all of Rockbuster's data into a relational database management system, then used SQL to analyze the data and answered any ad-hoc business questions the management board had.
- Presented the SQL results to the business manager by creating compelling dashboard stories and reports.
- Technical Scope: Tableau, GitHub, RDBMS, Db Visualizer, and Data Dictionary.

US Flu Predictive Analysis, CareerFoundry

June 2020

- Provided information to support a staffing plan, detailing what can help inform the timing and spatial distribution of medical personnel throughout the United States.
- Determined whether influenza occurs seasonally or throughout the entire year using Pivot Table
- Presented the conclusions, recommendations, and proposed next steps in final presentations and reports.
- Technical Scope: Excel, Tableau, Data Profiling, Statistical Hypothesis Testing, Spatial Analysis, and VLOOPUP.

EDUCATION

Data Immersion Certificate, CareerFoundryFeb 2021Bachelor of Business Analytics, University of Ottawa2018 – 2021Data Analytics Certificate, CareerFoundryJune 2020Introduction to Python for Data Science course, edXMay 2020Project Management Certificate, Algonquin College.Aug 2017